Zeinab Abu

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

London | 07958375242 | zeinababu@rocketmail.com | LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Effective problem solver and an excellent communicator with over 5 years of experience in the tech industry. Passionate about producing optimized code for readability, efficiency, and performance. Highly organized with years of experience organizing and designating work based on product requirements, often outside of the frontend department, helping to drive projects forward, while also contributing to the efficiency of the agile processes of the team. I focused on self-study and continuous learning on my way to becoming a full-stack developer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, HTML, React, Git, GitHub, CSS Modules, Next.js, Python, MySQL, PHP, BootStrap, JQuery

WORK EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER AskCoral | Remote | December 2022 - September 2023

- Using tools and frameworks within the React ecosystem such as, React Hooks, React Router, and CSS Modules.
- Using Storybook to help design components.
- Developing UIs when needed using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap in the Next.JS development environment.

Operations Manager (Nov 20 - May 23)

Bookkeeper and Payroll Adviser (May 18 - Nov 20)

OPERATIONS MANAGER Osteo-Ti | London | Jan 2015 - May 2018

- Responsible for all operational aspects of the business, including but not limited to Finance, Admin, HR, and Logistics.
- Developed, recommended, and implemented strategies to improve employee work quality and speed.
- Analyzed operations data to identify process gaps and successfully implemented change.

MARKETING AND EVENTS MANAGER Gronroos Media | London | May 2014 - Oct 2015

- Generate and manage new corporate business. Create and execute PowerPoint presentations for current and potential clients.
- Create an in-house database for target marketing through email, and web-based communications, Facebook, and Twitter.
- Work with the director of marketing and director of sales to organize and staff customer and sponsored events.

EDUCATION

DIGITAL SKILLS BOOTCAMP: SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT(12 Weeks) | JustIT Training Ltd, London 2023 - Present

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER | IT Career Switch, London 2023 - Present

FRONTEND DEVELOPER | SheCodes, London 2022 - 2023

BA (HONS) IN BUSINESS ADMIN AND QUANTITATIVE METHODS (2:1) | LSBU, London 2008 - 2011

PROJECT

React Weather App React Dictionary My Portfolio

JS Weather App

<u>Calculator</u> <u>Music Player</u>